The Crown Prince
sent me an ink stick?
Yes.
This is an ink stick blended with
old mountain sandalwood from Tianzhu.
Your Highness is truly an expert.
It's a top-grade old mountain
incense, a tribute from Xuancheng.
The craftsmanship is complex.
Only one stick can be made per year.
Second Prince is skilled
in painting.
Before, His Majesty
only ever gifted it to him.
Crown Prince specifically
requested this from His Majesty
to give to you, Your Highness.
Then I must thank the Crown Prince
for his generosity.
Yes.
Such a precious ink stick.
I must store it carefully
for Your Highness.
Zhen Zhu.
Take this ink stick
and give it to Second Prince.
But why?
He gave me the Incense Record.
I cannot accept a reward
I haven't earned.
It's proper to return a favor.
Are you sure you want to give it away?
Since it's something he loves,
why should I compete for it?
All of Crown Prince's efforts
were for nothing.
Don't look so glum.
The Moon Festival is in a few days.
I'll take you and Mo Yu
out to see the lanterns
and admire the moon.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 5=
Your Highness.
From here, you can look up
to see the full moon
and look down to see the city streets.
It's the best spot
in this entire restaurant.
Your Highness,
the Crown Prince proposed to you
in public.
Prince Lie is deeply devoted.
I can tell
his eyes are full of sincerity.
And then there's Prince Ning.
He seems to be a rare
and upright gentleman.
I want to help you figure it out,
but I don't know where to start.
Everyone wears a mask.
How can one see through them so easily?
It's a rare chance for us to be out.
Let's not think about other things.
Look.
According to the portrait
Mo Yuan gave us,
that man is clearly the real Hua Fuhai.
And the handsome man beside him
is the serious-looking one.
That's Cui Jinbai, Vice Minister
of the Court of Judicial Review.
This third person
has broad shoulders,
and a steady posture,
yet his steps are as light
as if walking on snow.
He must be a martial arts expert.
He's with Hua Fuhai and Cui Jinbai.
It's highly likely
that he's the real Embroidered Envoy.
They both answer to him.
Maybe
he's the Tagara Incense.
Reporting to Your Highness.
The fugitive officials involved
in the rouge case...
Vice Minister Cui and I,
following your instructions,
(Zhao Zhenghao, Embroidered Envoy)
have assigned
low-born yet talented scholars
to capture them.
(Hua Fuhai, Richest Hua Family's Eldest Son)
They've performed with great distinction.
They've all been promoted.
You've handled this matter well.
(Cui Jinbai, Vice Minister
of the Court of Judicial Review)
The four talented young men
Your Highness selected
have entered the Ministry of Revenue
and the Ministry of Personnel.
They have trained for many years
in the countryside.
Fit for great tasks.
You ordered us to continue investigating
the leads on the sale
of the rare poison.
I have already established
all the trade routes from Shunan
to the Western Regions.
And I've planted my own informants
at every post station.
Thank you for your hard work.
Awesome.
Wait for me here.
I'll be right back.
The show is about to begin.
- Come on, hurry!
- Come on!
There are paintings on the lanterns.
What are they of?
That one is
"Seeing a Gentleman Off to War."
This one is "A Couple's Mutual Respect."
So beautiful.
♪Flowers wilt and bloom again♪
♪In an endless cycle♪
A happy union.
Isn't this about being
a couple for a lifetime?
Which young master is this?
Going to such lengths for his beloved.
Indeed.
It's truly enviable.
Awesome.
♪Alone for several autumns♪
♪How to choose the one♪
♪To be with forever?♪
♪When I gaze upon you♪
♪Flower petals twirl gently in my heart♪
♪Gracefully♪
♪For all eternity♪
♪The timeless wind and moon♪
♪Quietly reflect in your sparkling eyes♪
♪Scattered red petals fall like rain♪
♪It's a wonderful time in the world♪
♪Bits of worries and sorrows♪
♪Are gently gathered
into your elegant sleeves♪
♪Gradually, on the misty path♪
♪Not a trace of sorrow can be found♪
(Lanxuan Incense and Ink Shop)
Young Lady Shen.
My young master requests your presence.
Greetings, Your Highness.
You're being so distant.
Are you still angry with me, Ruo?
Your Highness,
I don't understand what you mean.
When your mother passed away,
I knew you were heartbroken.
I wanted to pay my respects.
My mother was a concubine.
She could not have a memorial hall.
Nor could she
have outsiders pay respects.
In your eyes,
am I also an outsider?
Men and women should
keep their distance.
Please do not be so forward,
Your Highness.
I'll take my leave.
What if I don't allow it?
Your Highness, your actions
are truly improper.
Then tell me,
what is the real reason
you're so determined
to cut ties with me?
At six, I entered the palace
by imperial decree
to be Princess Pingling's
study companion.
I was young and homesick.
Then I met you, Your Highness.
When I was sad,
you let me cry on your shoulder.
Later on,
after your wife passed away,
you said you wouldn't remarry
and that you would wait for me
to grow up.
I have never lied to you.
But when my mother was imprisoned,
I begged you to take me to see her,
and you flatly refused.
That's when I knew
that in your heart,
fame,
and power
are all more important than me.
And just as I thought,
you publicly proposed
to my older sister.
Even if I marry your sister,
there are still many ways
for us to be together.
Your Highness,
don't destroy the image I have of you
in my heart.
And don't forget,
my surname is also Shen.
My sister and I are not close,
but the happiness I want
is not built upon her misfortune.
But in Shen Xihe's eyes,
she has never truly considered you
a member of the Shen family.
That's not important.
As long as I act like a Shen,
that's enough.
I will always remember
that the one who was
my scholarly companion
was you.
Nanny.
Your Ladyship,
don't be sad.
My mother resented me
for not being a boy.
She would either beat or scold me.
In all those years,
he was the only one
who showed me any warmth.
Nanny.
(Duke of Wei's Manor)
Xihe.
(Old Mountain Sandalwood from Tianzhu?)
Yingruo.
We two sisters
have never sat down for a proper chat.
Since we have time today,
may I trouble you for a moment
in your room?
Please, Xihe.
Please have some tea, Xihe.
Have you known the Second Prince
for a long time?
No.
I don't know him.
You entered the palace as
a study companion when you were young.
The palace holds
festive banquets every year,
as well as outings and hunts.
The princes and noble ladies
have all met.
It would be normal for you to know him.
Why would you say you don't?
I have seen him at banquets before,
but we only exchanged nods.
We are not well-acquainted.
Some time ago,
I sent an ink stick mixed with
Old Mountain Sandalwood from Tianzhu
to the Second Prince.
This incense is rare
and long-lasting.
When he was using this ink,
you were by his side.
Were you perhaps his scholarly muse,
lending your fragrance
to his brush and ink?
I... I didn't.
Still denying it?
You might as well smell
the fragrance on yourself.
In my opinion,
your relationship with him
can be described as quite intimate.
You disregarded propriety
to have a secret affair with him.
And yet, he asked His Majesty
for my hand in marriage.
Could it be that you were thinking
that we two sisters
would marry
into Second Prince's Manor together?
No.
I never thought of competing with you.
It's just that...
You just can't forget
those empty promises he made to you?
Or are you unwilling to part
with these scrolls in your room,
which carry the scent
of Old Mountain Sandalwood?
Xihe, your wisdom is unparalleled.
You see things with perfect clarity.
I am far behind you.
Over all these years,
I did indeed turn my gratitude
and respect for His Highness
into affection.
But if you marry him,
I will have no resentment in my heart.
As for these scrolls,
I'm just keeping them as a memento.
So you plan
to just look at these scrolls
for the rest of your life?
Because of this worthless affection,
you'll throw away your own future?
I...
Let me make things clear today.
I will not choose the Second Prince
as my husband.
But I won't let you marry him either.
Sweet nothings and vows of eternal love
are tactics that require
no cost at all.
Of course he says them so easily.
By asking to marry me,
he has betrayed you.
How can you be so blind?
My mother died because of Xiao.
It's true that you and I are not fated
to be as close as other sisters.
But that doesn't prevent
each of us from living a wonderful life.
Xihe, you want me
to live a wonderful life?
Why not?
I don't like you,
but I don't dislike you either.
The grudge between your mother and me
has nothing to do with you.
I won't involve the innocent.
But the Second Prince
is truly not someone
you can entrust your life to.
I can't bear
to see you sink into this mire.
Shen Yingruo,
you are also a daughter
of the Duke of Wei.
I advise you not
to look down on yourself.
You need to stand taller
and look further ahead.
Only then will you discover
that there are many other things
worthy of dedicating your life to.
Xihe,
I was wrong.
I'll go burn the scrolls in a moment.
Your Highness,
it's done.
Commandery Princess, through
that Old Mountain Sandalwood ink stick,
has discovered Second Prince's
affair with her sister, Yingruo.
(Prince Ning, Xiao Changmin)
So soon you have a favor to ask of me?
Your Highness, you don't know
that the rouge case has concluded.
To celebrate the victory,
His Majesty had Noble Consort Rong
host a flower-viewing banquet
in the Hibiscus Garden.
Many ladies from noble families
were invited.
This is a good thing.
Why the long face?
It's called flower-viewing,
but it's really a matchmaking event.
And I've received reliable information
that Princess Anling
wants to take me as her prince consort.
Your Highness,
do you have a way to save me?
You are the only son
of the Marquis of Shunan.
Of course you're expected
to marry a princess.
Only you know my true identity.
As a lady, how am I supposed to
go through with the wedding night?
Have you forgotten my rule?
No personal feelings,
only business?
I'll give the northwestern army
3,000 sets of fine armor.
Then at tomorrow's
flower-viewing banquet,
we'll go together.
The flowers over there
are blooming beautifully.
- Let's go.
- You're here too.
You're here, too.
Slow down.
The flowers over there are pretty too.
Sister Huang,
these flowers are so beautiful.
I like this orange one.
Announcing Commandery Princess Zhaoning!
That's Commandery Princess Zhaoning.
- Her Highness has an elegant class.
- So it's her.
Have you heard?
His Majesty is letting her choose
her own husband from among the princes.
Prince Yu and Prince Ning
are vying for her affection.
Prince Lie promised her
a lifetime of monogamy.
Even the Crown Prince
has fallen for her.
She's so lucky.
Well, she is indeed beautiful.
Yes.
Greetings, Noble Consort Rong.
Your Highness, please rise.
This is Princess Anling.
(Princess Anling)
You two are of similar age.
You can keep each other company.
I'm a year younger than you.
Then I'll call you Sister Zhaoning.
This is the Taiji Hall.
And this is the Imperial Garden.
Your Highness, did you know
(Princess Pingling)
that in northwest, they often eat cats?
Of course I know.
Pingling, what are you talking about?
We were talking about our pet cats.
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
is from northwest.
I've heard northwest is barren,
and the barbarians there
will eat anything.
They often stew and eat cats.
- They even eat cats?
- Really?
During the late emperor's reign,
the Le clan invaded our borders
more than ten times a year.
The men and women of northwest
fought bravely to defend us.
To survive,
they dug for rats and drank snake blood.
It is because of them that you can now
live peacefully in the capital
and play with your pet cats.
What right do you
have to insult northwest?
If not for the ferocity
of the people of northwest,
you might right now
be lying in the tent of a Le Clan King,
barely clothed.
You...
Your Highness seems to imply
that the peace of this realm
is all thanks to northwest.
The young lady of the Chen family
insulted northwest,
so I spoke to her about northwest.
Young lady of the Wang family,
you insist on bringing up
the peace of the realm.
I would like to know
what contribution the Wang family
has made to this peace
that gives you the right
to disregard all etiquette
and rashly interrupt others.
My upbringing is different from yours.
There's no need to force ourselves
to get along.
(Hu Yingrao)
Sister Xihe, I finally found you.
Have you thought
of a way to help me get rid
of Princess Anling?
Even if I help you put an end
to Princess Anling's intentions today,
there are still Princess Pingling
and Princess Changling.
His Majesty will eventually
choose a princess for you.
If you're worried about your identity
as a lady being exposed,
we have to solve the problem
at its root.
Then what should I do?
I've found an excellent candidate
for you.
Go and befriend him.
Stick to him day in and day out,
be inseparable.
As long as he's around,
those young ladies
won't dare come near you.
Who is it? Someone
with such a magical effect?
Vice Minister of the Court
of Judicial Review, Cui Jinbai.
Cui Jinbai?
That clueless blockhead, Stone Cui?
Why him of all people?
In the current imperial court,
he is the most upright
and talented young man.
He avoids all romantic dalliances
and flirtatious women.
He's also a trusted minister
of His Majesty
and is being groomed
as a future chancellor.
If you're with him every day,
how would those princesses
dare to pester you?
That makes sense.
Vice Minister Cui.
Why are you sitting here
all by yourself?
I've been looking all over for you.
Captain Bu, what business
do you have with me?
You're in charge of trials
at the Court of Judicial Review.
As a member of the Imperial Guard,
I'm responsible for patrolling
the capital and enforcing the curfew.
Logically speaking, we're colleagues.
So,
I wanted to take this opportunity
at the Noble Consort's banquet
to befriend you.
Unnecessary.
Why did you reject me so bluntly?
Have I offended you in some way?
His Majesty values
the Marquis of Shunan,
which is why he allowed you
into the Imperial Guard.
The position he granted you
is not a low one.
But what have you done?
You frequent taverns and music halls,
partying every night.
You spend all day carousing
with courtesans.
Whenever you report
on the capital's situation,
you stammer
and can't give a straight answer.
Yet you can recite the names
of courtesans without a second thought.
I have no interest
in being friends with someone like you.
Jinbai,
it seems you have quite
a misunderstanding about me.
Come, come.
Let me have a good chat with you
and clear this up.
You lecher.
Someone fell in the water!
Someone fell in!
Someone, help!
Help!
Help! I can't swim!
Here.
Help! Help!
I can't swim!
Help!
Help! I can't swim!
Are you insane?
Someone could die because of this!
Stop it now!
So you do know that someone could die.
I thought you didn't.
If you kill someone,
you'll pay with your life.
Of course you pay with your life
for killing someone.
But I'm saving someone.
Help!
- It's just that...
- Help!
my aim was off.
What's going on?
- I hope nothing bad happens.
- Look at this.
Grab the pole!
Quick!
What is all this commotion?
Your Majesty,
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
pushed me into the lake.
She even hit me with a bamboo pole
and wouldn't let me get out.
She was trying to drown me!
Your Majesty,
Young Lady Hu deliberately tried
to push me into the lake.
Luckily, I dodged in time.
Otherwise, I would've been
the one in the lake.
It all started
when Young Lady Chen kept insisting
that the people
of northwest are barbarians.
I argued with her for a bit.
The young lady of the Wang family
accused me of elevating northwest.
Seeing that I was on bad terms
with the two young ladies,
Young Lady Hu wanted
to stand up for them.
Your Majesty,
to call the people
of northwest barbarians
is to harbor intentions
of dividing the nation.
Such intentions are punishable by death.
Your Majesty,
I believe
there must be a misunderstanding.
These young ladies have been raised
in seclusion their whole lives.
They learn flower arranging
and practice needlework.
They read nothing more than Admonitions
for Ladies and Rules for Ladies.
How could they be so reckless
as to carelessly discuss
matters of state?
Your Majesty, please see the truth.
These words
could not have truly come
from these young ladies.
They have never been to northwest.
How could they possibly look down on it?
They must have simply heard
some reckless talk somewhere
and are merely repeating it.
The Crown Prince is wise and just.
The young ladies of our families
have been spared a false accusation.
Thank you, Your Highness.
A child's words and actions
are taught by their parents.
This young lady was raised in seclusion.
If she hadn't heard nonsense
from her elders,
how would she know to sow discord
among court officials?
I ask Your Majesty
to investigate this thoroughly.
Do not tolerate such
wicked people who have no regard
for the court, their sovereign,
or the common folk.
Your Majesty, if I may.
The heavens are always watching.
My loyalty to you is as clear as day.
My disobedient daughter's reckless words
were certainly not taught by me.
Your Majesty,
I also do not know
where my unfilial daughter
heard such arrogant words.
I have failed in raising my daughter.
I am willing to accept punishment.
Your Majesty,
my daughter is young
and knows nothing of politics.
It is I who raised her to be ignorant.
That is why she is so reckless.
Please punish me, Your Majesty.
Rest assured, Commandery Princess.
The great families have
been strict in raising their kids.
When they mention punishment,
it is not just empty words.
Attendant Wang.
Vice Minister Hu.
Marquis of Xuanping.
The three of you, for your failure
to discipline your families,
will be fined one year's salary.
You will reflect on your wrongdoings
for ten days
and submit a letter of repentance.
- Thank Your Majesty for your grace.
Changqing,
what's wrong with you?
It's nothing.
Thank you for what you did just now,
Your Highness.
Those young ladies were the ones
who bullied you first.
They deserved to be punished.
You've had a long day.
You should get some rest.
A thousand lights
on a spring night's path.
Ten miles of silk under a moonlit sky.
Commandery Princess,
tonight will be a fine night.
This street has always been dark
and difficult to walk on.
Why are there suddenly so many lanterns?
Tonight
is indeed a fine night.
Your Highness,
this is the cold-warding incense
sent by Commandery Princess.
She must have seen that I was sensitive
to the cold at the hunting grounds.
Go find an incense burner.
Commandery Princess said
that she personally
improved this formula.
Not only does it retain its warmth,
but it also has a calming effect.
Indeed.
Commandery Princess
has exceptional taste.
The incense she blends
is naturally excellent.
Then I must tell you
something harsh.
What do you mean?
Commandery Princess has sent people
to inquire about your medical records.
Is that so?
Commandery Princess
is concerned about my health.
In previous years,
when those ministers and princes
inquired about your medical records,
you always said
they had ulterior motives.
How is it that when it comes to her,
it's a sign of her concern for you?
My second and sixth brothers
have disappointed her one after another.
For her to inquire
about my medical records now
means she must be considering me
as a potential husband.
That's why she wants
to know about my lifespan.
Never mind.
A three-part self-hypnosis.
How could Commandery Princess
possibly have any bad intentions?
How could she not be kind?
How could she have ulterior motives?
Have the Imperial Medical Office
send her my records.
Don't hide anything from her.
Didn't you say
you had no real intention
of proposing marriage?
After my coming-of-age ceremony,
my father, the Emperor,
and the Empress Dowager
will choose a crown princess for me.
I just think that
if it were Commandery Princess Zhaoning,
life in the East Palace
would certainly be interesting.
Whatever you say is right,
Your Highness.
The Starvine Moss has been growing
exceptionally well lately.
Tomorrow,
invite Commandery Princess
to admire it with me.
Yes.
Tian Yuan said
that this rare Starvine Moss
was specially cultivated
by the Crown Prince for you.
He cares for it day and night.
How thoughtful.
You said you weren't
considering the Crown Prince,
so why did you have someone
send him cold-warding incense?
And you even had Mo Yuan go
to the Imperial Medical Office
to check his medical records.
This has nothing to do with affection.
You saw the records. What did they say?
Judging from the medical records alone,
he is undoubtedly frail.
As for his lifespan,
it's impossible to determine.
I have never met anyone
like Xiao Huayong.
He's gentle and modest,
perfectly so.
It's impossible to discern his motives.
If he truly doesn't have long to live,
then there's no need for him to pretend.
It would mean he is
a truly pure and kind person.
But if the opposite is true,
then he is biding his time
and hiding his true strength.
He is incredibly shrewd.
Compared to the other princes,
I still can't see through him.
So, are we still going
to the East Palace?
Of course, we are.
Given the current situation,
he is one of my choices for a husband.
I must see clearly
what kind of person he truly is.
(East Palace)
It will be a little later
before it's the best time
to view the Starvine Moss.
Please have some tea
and snacks first, Commandery Princess.
This Mijin is a flower cake that every
household in the imperial capital eats.
During the Double Ninth Festival,
the capital is at its liveliest.
Drinking chrysanthemum liquor,
eating flower cakes,
wearing dogwood sprigs
and chrysanthemum hairpins,
and climbing to a high place
are all essential traditions.
With my health, drinking chrysanthemum
liquor and climbing to a high place
are out of the question for me.
Climbing to a high place doesn't have
to mean climbing a tall mountain.
It could be a high tower.
In the past,
on every Double Ninth Festival,
my father and brother
would accompany me to the top
of the city tower at Northwest Pass
to watch the city lit up
like a tree of fire and silver flowers.
It was a magnificent sight.
From the imperial capital's city tower,
you can also take in
the whole splendid view.
If, during the Double Ninth Festival,
my health is holding up,
would you be willing
to ascend the tower with me?
Yes.
These few books
are all quite obscure.
They are travelogues by folk scholars
who journeyed far and wide,
seeking out wonders and scenic spots.
I cannot travel the world,
but my heart yearns for it.
My only hobby is reading.
When I read,
I feel like I'm right there
in the story.
Me too.
Why don't we each
write down a favorite line
and exchange them?
Excellent idea.
(A strong army conquers others.
Strong people conquer fate.)
It seems you and I
are kindred spirits.
I am deeply honored.
Commandery Princess,
come with me to the pond.
This is the Starvine Moss,
a tribute from the Western Regions.
You've always liked rare flowers
and exotic plants.
I'm sure you'll like it.
Such a wondrous sight.
This is my first time seeing it as well.
♪Pushing the sea of stars
to flow across♪
This moss comes alive in water,
shimmering dazzlingly.
It's also called Night-Luminescent Moss.
♪In an endless cycle♪
♪Amidst the flickering lights♪
♪Alone for several autumns♪
Don't be afraid, Commandery Princess.
The moss follows the current
and clings to the nearest fabric.
♪When I gaze upon you♪
♪Flower petals twirl gently in my heart♪
♪Life and death are mottled♪
♪Only the threads of love are exquisite♪
♪Hidden in the depths of your eyes♪
♪An autumn lake reflects you and I♪
♪As the years go by♪
Don't worry.
The Starvine Moss withers
once it's out of water.
♪A pool of you♪
♪And a pool of me♪
Do you know
why it withers out of water?
Because it was born
immersed in the gaze of a lover.
Although I find Commandery Princess
quite scheming,
I still prefer His Highness like this,
when he's trying to woo a lady,
he's so full of life and vigor.
(Cultivate virtue
and practice righteousness)
Your Highness.
Physician Xie said
he found a rare prescription
among the common folk.
This medicine can regulate
the internal organs
and suppress the poison.
However, this medicine is
extremely potent with yang energy.
Your constitution is cold and weak.
He's afraid that each time
you undergo treatment,
you'll endure pain
akin to scraping bone and cutting flesh.
How long will the pain last?
Two hours.
I'll try it.
I know the Duke has his heart
set on me as his ideal son-in-law.
I'll ask you one more time.
Will you marry me?
I will not.
Shen Xihe, stop right there!
Commandery Princess Zhaoning
has come a long way from northwest,
but her incense-blending technique
is identical to that
of the Prince Xin's Consort.
There's not the slightest difference.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪